Hi I'm Kelli and I am an Aesthetician and makeup artist At Ulta Salon and Cosmetics and I'm going to give you some tips to clear skin.
Basically the easiest way to remember what to do is to look at the acronym for acne.
Basically what you want to do is make sure you are using antibacterial products, make sure you are using a really good antibacterial cleanser.
Basically what causes acne is when you have dirt and debris and oil clogged within a pore and it becomes infected by that P.acne bacteria.
So just by using antibacterial products to help to kill that P.acne bacteria you are going to lessen the likelihood of breakout.
You also want to use oil controlling products typically acneic skin is caused from an over production of oil so just by using oil free products, hydrating products and products like something like microsponging it or something that is going to be oil controlling definitely help.
Salicylic acid is a really great ingredient for that as well.
You also want to use nonirritating products.
You never want to use anything that is abrasive on the skin or anything that is going to overstrip the skin or you never want to scrub over an open blemish.
That is just going to spread the bacteria.
It is going to lead to inflammation and it is going to lead to scarring but you do want to make sure that exfoliate.
Anybody with acneic skin produces up to four times the amount of dead skin cells of the person with average skin so you want to definitely make sure that you use a lot of exfoliating products.
I like to use salicylic acid for those types of exfoliation because chemical exfoliants helps keep the pores really nice and clean and helps to control the oil and are nonirritating.
So those are some things you can do for clear skin.